fragomen.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy policies | Fragomen

We appreciate your interest in our firm. Before communicating with us by email, please understand that unless you are an existing client of the Firm, any information sent will not be confidential. By clicking 'OK' below, you acknowledge and understand that (i) where applicable, contacting us will not create any attorney-client relationship between you and Fragomen or any attorney at the Firm and (ii) any information transmitted will not be treated as confidential. Thank you for your interest; we look forward to hearing from you.

###### Privacy Policies, Notices and Statements

EFFECTIVE DATE: May 14, 2018

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, and our related affiliates and subsidiaries* (collectively, “Fragomen” or "we") want to ensure that our clients, their employees, and any affected data subjects ("you") are informed about the security and use of the personal information that we receive and process on your behalf. 

Accordingly, this Privacy Notice (“Privacy Notice”) is intended to inform you about Fragomen’s privacy practices. It describes the types of personal information we collect, how we may use that information, with whom it may be shared and the measures taken to ensure its security.

In addition, we provide information on how to contact us to: (1) exercise your right to object to the processing of certain aspects of your personal information in accordance with applicable laws; (2) access, correct, or delete your personal information; (3) ask any questions you may have about our privacy practices.

In some instances we are engaged directly by corporations or business groups, which results in the processing of employee information at their request. Where we refer to “employer” below, it is in these circumstances where corporations or other business groups have engaged us to act. You may at any time, if you prefer, address any concerns directly to your employer, where applicable.  
​

_*A complete list of Fragomen entities and affiliates with contact details can be found here:  [Fragomen Office-US](https://www.fragomen.com/about/offices/us/)._

Fragomen collects certain personal information about you and, if required, your family members and employer for the purposes of providing immigration consulting and legal services.  We will not be able to provide the services requested if we are not provided with all relevant personal information.  Below are set forth the purposes for which personal information is used and examples of the types of information that may be required. If, through the course of our representation, you and/or your employer request additional services, such as visa extensions, permanent residency applications and changes in employment, we may be required to collect additional types of personal information to provide the requested services.

For purposes of providing client services, including the applicable legal services, and/or immigration consulting services you and/or your employer request, Fragomen collects and processes personal information such as name, address, telephone number, date of birth, marital status, passport number, employment history, educational background, tax status, employee number, job title and function, and expatriate status. Where required for the service, Fragomen collects certain personal documents such as passport copies, educational documents, CVs, visa copies, birth certificates, and other documents.

We obtain the personal information from a number of sources, such as through our online portals, our mobile website or applications, online questionnaires and forms you complete, and other information you provide directly to us, including by email or in conversation with our lawyers, consultants and staff.  In addition, we obtain personal information from third-party sources, such as former employers, educational institutions you attended, relocation companies, and your current or prospective employer.  We use this information to provide immigration consulting and legal services, including analyzing, completing and processing immigration, visa and related filings and submissions to relevant government agencies, providing legal and consultative advice as to eligibility to obtain immigration benefits, and assisting with relocation and other expatriate issues.

In many instances such as visa extensions, permanent residency, and other cases related to changes in employment, the services we provide require follow-up services. If such follow-up is required, the information we have collected previously is used to provide the additional related services for which we have been engaged.

We also use your personal information in other instances in connection with the services we provide. This use occurs only when there is a legitimate interest to do so that is not overridden by your data protection rights as required by law, such as assisting in the management and administration of our clients’ global mobility programs (such as visa expiration tracking, immigration program compliance, etc.), providing access to online case-management tools, where applicable, and analyzing immigration trends, such as visa processing times and government approval rates. Where we are engaged by your employer, we process your personal information because it is in our legitimate interests to do so in order to fulfil our contract with your employer for client services.

In addition to providing you or your employer with our services, we process personal information to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations including record-keeping requirements. For example, we process personal information under “know your customer”, anti-money laundering regulations, anti-bribery regulations and professional regulations. 

**PRE-EMPLOYMENT VERIFICATION** ** **

Certain countries require verification of new employees’ employment eligibility at the time of hire.  Examples of such requirements include the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (“ **IRCA** ”) in the United States and the Immigration, Asylum & Nationality Act of 2006 in the United Kingdom, pursuant to which Fragomen collects and processes personal information such as your name, email address, home address, military service, and citizenship status. 

**INFORMATION REQUESTS** ** **

If you request information about our services directly, you may choose to provide personal information such as your name, address, email address and telephone number.  We use your information to respond to your request.

Fragomen's Business Visa Matrix (BVM) is a web-based tool that assesses whether a business traveler may lawfully conduct planned activities abroad on business visitor status or whether work authorization is required. If you choose to use this service, we will provide an automated assessment, using the information provided by the user and based on local immigration law requirements, to assist in the determination of what immigration requirements may be necessary for travel to or within a particular country.

Where it is in our legitimate interests and not outweighed by your data protection rights, we use personal information we collect and process for client and Fragomen administration, compliance audits, compliance with Fragomen policies and procedures, ensuring the security and integrity of our services and in ensuring that our IT systems function effectively.

In addition, we process your personal information with your consent, such as when we use your contact details to respond to a request or question by you, or where required by law.

**SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Governments worldwide require the collection and processing of a wide variety of personal information from foreign nationals seeking to enter the country and obtain immigration benefits such as employment authorization or residency status. Governments require this information for reasons such as the protection of borders, health, sovereignty, national security, and the regulation of the local employment market. Certain categories of personal information may be considered “sensitive” and are subject to a higher level of data protection. These categories may include race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, sex life or sexual orientation, physical or mental health or condition, data relating to offenses and/or criminal convictions, and biometric data, such as fingerprints, when used to uniquely identify you.

In the context of the services we provide, Fragomen collects sensitive personal information when the submission of such data is necessary to comply with the legal obligations of the country in which you are seeking a visa or work permit. In addition, Fragomen may need to inquire about certain sensitive information in order to provide legal or consultative advice as to your eligibility to travel to or obtain an immigration benefit from a specific country. For instance, we may need to ask whether you have been previously convicted of any criminal offenses, have certain political affiliations, or other personal matters when the local applicable immigration laws would require such data for purposes of preparing an application or petition on your behalf or evaluating whether certain personal information would bar you from entering the country. In some instances, the laws of EU member states require that we process sensitive personal information for these purposes as permitted by the terms of the GDPR; on other occasions we will ask for your explicit consent to process this data.

In the course of our client services, we may represent you and/or your employer in legal matters that require us to collect and use sensitive personal information relating to you. For example, if we represent you in a criminal case, we will collect information about the alleged offenses and any related criminal history. In some employment representations, such as disputes involving alleged discrimination, information about medical conditions, race, religion and/or sexual orientation may be relevant to the representation. Similarly, representations in tax or social security matters may also require us to collect sensitive personal information, such as if we are advising on whether certain disabilities qualify for social security or tax benefits. Where we process sensitive personal information in the course of these and other similar client services, we do so to assist you and/or your employer to establish, exercise or defend legal claims or to assist you and/or your employer in fulfilling the rights and obligations of applicable employment or social security laws.

We use cookies and related technologies on our websites and other web-based interfaces, such as Fragomen Connect, employer-specific Immigration Home Page Applications, our mobile website and applications, and the BUSINESS VISA MATRIX™. We use these technologies to understand how many users visited our sites and the pages they accessed so that we can best tailor our web services to our visitors.  

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites that help collect data. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features.

Log files are web server files (containing information such as domain name or IP address, URL, http response code, or the date and duration of your visit) that are automatically created when an Internet user visits a website. An IP address is an identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our website, our servers log your IP address. In combination with other data, this information helps us understand which features are of interest to our visitors and the regions of the world where these visitors are located. In addition, log files help detect disruptions that may interfere with the provision of our website.

We will not sell, share, transfer, rent, use, or distribute your information for purposes other than those disclosed here unless required by law or as authorized by you or your employer. We share the information you provide among our subsidiaries, affiliates and your current or prospective employer or a third party as your employer instructs us, as appropriate or necessary in connection with the services (such as your employer’s relocation provider, or to protect the interests of any person, where permitted by applicable law. Where our services are retained by your employer on your behalf, we share your personal information as instructed by your employer, for tax purposes, to assist you in obtaining relocation services, and for any other purpose required to provide the services as permitted by applicable law.

In addition, as part of the immigration consulting and legal services we have been directed to provide, Fragomen discloses personal information to government agencies, your former, current, or prospective employer and its related entities. In order to obtain immigration benefits on your or your employer’s behalf, we will disclose personal information to government agencies and immigration authorities.  

We also share the information with certain service providers we have retained in connection with the services we provide, such as translators, education evaluation services, couriers, or other necessary entities. We take steps to require that service providers protect the information consistently with this Privacy Notice.  These service providers are authorized to use the information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with law or legal process. Where we have knowledge that a service provider processes your personal information in a manner contrary to this Privacy Notice, we will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing. In addition, we will disclose information about you: (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (4) if necessary to protect the vital interests of any person.

We seek to ensure that any personal information that we hold about you is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable based on data you or an employer provide in order to provide the immigration consulting and legal services. We seek to collect only that personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for these purposes.

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical, organizational, and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction of personal information.

We educate our employees and strive to maintain appropriate standards of conduct with regard to the protection of personal information.

We take steps to require that third parties who assist in our provision of services abide by all applicable privacy and data protection laws and prohibit them from using your information other than in connection with the services they have been engaged to provide.

We retain personal information for only as long as we need it to provide the services you or your employer has requested, for our own administration and internal purposes, and for any periods that are mandated by law or otherwise agreed to with our clients, after which, we take steps to delete or anonymize the information.

**_Transfers required for the services_**

When we transfer your information to other countries, we will use, share and safeguard that information as described in this Privacy Notice.  We transfer personal information to third countries where it is necessary to provide you the service you (or your employer) requested. For example, the Government requires certain personal information in order to review applications, screen foreign nationals, issue visas and other work authorization documents, etc. We also provide your personal information to local advisors, translators and other service providers where it is necessary to provide the service you requested.

**_Transfers to other Fragomen offices_**

We share some of your personal information with other Fragomen offices to administer and manage group functions and provide international advisory services. For these purposes, your personal information will be processed in, or accessed from, Fragomen offices situated in jurisdictions that do not have equivalent data protection laws to those in your country of residence.

In addition, some of our global systems for providing services are hosted by our offices in the United States. We safeguard your data within the Fragomen group of companies through the use of European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses.

**_Transfers to other service providers_**

Your personal information will be shared with companies providing services under contract to us for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice, some of which are located outside the EEA. If you reside in the EEA, we may use standard contractual data protection clauses, which have been approved by the European Commission. We may also transfer your information to organisations in the US who participate in the EU-US Privacy Shield or which have binding corporate rules in place to protect your data, which have been approved by EU data protection authorities. For further information, including to obtain a copy of the documents used to protect your information, please contact us as described in the How to Contact Us section below.

As set out above, Fragomen may collect certain information about you in conjunction with providing immigration consulting and legal services. We will respect your decision if subsequently your employer informs us or, where you instruct us directly, you inform us that you wish to opt-out of personal information. If sensitive personal information is involved for the delivery of a new purpose we will only use your information if you actively communicate your consent to this processing to your employer or us, as applicable, when it is necessary to deliver requested service, or in accordance with the requirements of applicable laws. We will follow the identical procedure if we disclose personal information to third parties that are expected to process the personal information for their own independent purposes.

We also will assist our clients to provide you, or provide you directly, where appropriate, with access to your personal information and, as applicable, with the ability to review and correct inaccuracies, delete unnecessary personal information, and receive a copy of your personal information in a structured machine-readable format. We may, where applicable, use reasonable efforts to assist your employer in responding to a request to access, correct, delete or restrict processing of your personal information or, where required by law, to respond directly to such a request within a reasonable period of time. In the event that either you or your employer informs us in writing that you wish to opt-out of future processing of personal information we will respect your request.

To help protect your privacy and the security of your information, Fragomen takes reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to information. Where we rely solely on your consent, you may withdraw it at any time.  You may also object to processing that is based on our legitimate interests alone. In such instances, our business interests must be found to be compelling and to not jeopardize your individual rights before further processing may continue. To exercise these rights, please contact your employer or Fragomen, as applicable. If you have unresolved concerns, where provided by local law, you may have the right to complain to a data protection authority where you reside, where you work or where you believe there has been an infringement of data protection laws.

This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices. We will post a notice on our applicable websites or materials to advise of any significant changes to our Privacy Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated. In certain countries, additional or different procedures not inconsistent with this Privacy Notice may apply as necessary to satisfy local legal requirements.

The controllers for your personal information are Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP and the Fragomen office providing the services to you. Our representative in the European Union is Fragomen LLP, 95 Gresham Street, 1st Floor, London, EC2V 7NA, United Kingdom. If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice directed at any of the data controllers listed above, please contact our data protection officer by email at [ **dataprivacy@fragomen.com**. ](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com.%20)You also may write to us at:

Attn: Office of General Counsel

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP

90 Matawan Road

P.O. Box 2001

Matawan, New Jersey 07747

USA

_Last Updated: May 14, 2018_

___________________________________

EFFECTIVE DATE: May 18, 2018

This Privacy Notice describes the processing of your personal information by Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, and any of our related affiliates and subsidiaries worldwide[1] (collectively, " **Fragomen** " or " **we** ") for marketing purposes.

In addition, this Privacy Notice describes your data protection rights, including how you can object to our use of your personal information.

We collect and process the following personal information when you inquire about our services, sign up for newsletters and/or client alerts, or provide your information to our representatives at conferences and events:

  * _Contact information_

: Where you provide it to us, we collect contact data including your first name, last name, mailing address, telephone number, fax number, email address and other similar contact information.

  * _Preferences_

: We process information concerning your preferences and interests as they relate to Fragomen services, such as the newsletters and client alerts you sign up for, the types of Fragomen services you may be interested in hearing about and how you prefer to receive communications from us.

We also receive information about prospective clients from other sources, such as through referrals from existing clients and third-party referral agencies we engage.

We collect information on visitors to our websites through the use of cookies and similar technologies. We use this information to enable certain features of the websites, to understand how visitors use our websites and to allow us to improve the quality and content of our websites. For more information on our use of cookies and similar technologies, please consult our 

_Cookie Policy_

.[2]

We use personal information for the following purposes:

  * Where necessary for our legitimate interests, as listed below, and where these interests are not overridden by your data protection rights.

    * To provide you with information on services that may be relevant for you, to contact you about legal developments that may affect you, and to discuss potential business opportunities with you

    * To understand the preferences of our clients and potential clients and to assess how they engage with our services. 

  * Where you have given your consent.

    * We may contact you by email, telephone, post or fax in accordance with your consent, as specified by applicable law, and you may withdraw consent from receiving future marketing at any time.

If you engage our client services, we use your personal information in accordance with the 

_Fragomen Privacy Policy and Notice_

.[3]

We share some of your personal information with other Fragomen offices to provide you with information that will be relevant to your interests and to connect you with Fragomen lawyers or advisors who may be useful to you. For these purposes, your personal information will be processed in, or accessed from, Fragomen offices situated in jurisdictions that do not have equivalent data protection laws to those in your country of residence.

In addition, our global client relationship management systems are hosted by our offices in the United States. We safeguard your data within the Fragomen group of companies through the use of European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses.

Your personal information will be shared with companies providing services under contract to us for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice that may be located in a different country than you. When transferring your personal information, we rely on European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses with service providers or the service provider's adherence to the EU-US Privacy Shield or approved binding corporate rules that protect your information. For further information, including to obtain a copy of the documents used to protect your information, please contact us as described in the _How to contact us_ section below.

If you have any questions about our information handling practices or if you wish to access your personal information you should contact our Data Privacy Office at: [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com).  

**If you are based in the European Union**

You have the right to **ask us for a copy** of your personal information; to **correct** , **delete** or **restrict** processing of your personal information; and to **obtain the personal information you provide in a structured, machine readable format**. In addition, you can **object to the processing** of your personal information in some circumstances (in particular, where we don’t have to process the data to meet a contractual or other legal requirement). Where we have asked for your consent, you may **withdraw consent** at any time.

These **rights may be limited** , for example, if fulfilling your request would reveal personal information about another person, or if you ask us to delete information which we are required by law or have compelling legitimate interests to keep. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the **right to complain** to a data protection authority where you reside, where you work or where you believe there has been an infringement of data protection laws.

We will **retain** your personal information only for as long as we need it for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice, after which we will take steps to delete your personal information or hold it in a form that no longer identifies you. If you engage our services, we will retain your personal information in accordance with the 

_Fragomen Privacy Policy and Notice_

.

The data controllers for your personal information are the Fragomen office to which you provided your information, as well as Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP and Fragomen Global LLP. Our representative in the European Union is Fragomen LLP, 95 Gresham Street, 1st Floor, London, EC2V 7NA, United Kingdom. If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice directed at any of the data controllers above, please contact our data protection officer by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at:

Attn: Office of General Counsel

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP

90 Matawan Road

P.O. Box 2001

Matawan, New Jersey 07747

USA

* * *

[1] A complete list of Fragomen entities and affiliates with contact details can be found here: [Fragomen Office-US](https://www.fragomen.com/about/offices/us/).

___________________________________

**ONLINE PRIVACY NOTICE**

EFFECTIVE DATE: May 10, 2010

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, and their related affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively “Fragomen”) respect your concerns about privacy. This Online Privacy Notice applies only to personal information collected on [http://www.fragomen.com](http://www.fragomen.com/). This notice describes the types of personal information we collect on this website, how we may use that information and with whom we share it. Our Online Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. We also tell you how you can reach us to answer any questions you may have about our online privacy practices.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT  **

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

If you email us through the “Contact Us” link on this site, you may choose to provide personal information to us such as your name, email address, resume or CV. You may choose to provide additional information as well. We use the information you provide to respond to and communicate with you about your questions and comments. 

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT BY AUTOMATED MEANS**

We may collect certain information by automated means when you visit this website, such as how many users visited the site and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our websites to our visitors. We collect this information through “cookies” and IP addresses. 

**COOKIES**

Like many organizations, we may use “cookies” on this website. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features. 

**LOG FILES, USAGE DATA  AND IP ADDRESSES**

Log files are web server files (containing information such as domain name or IP address, URL, http response code, or the date and duration of your visit) that are automatically created when an Internet user visits a website. An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our website, our servers log your IP address. In combination with other data, this information helps us understand which features are of interest to our visitors and the regions of the world where these visitors are located. In addition, log files help detect disruptions that may interfere with the provision of our website. 

We do not disclose personal information about visitors to this website, except as described here. We will not sell, share, transfer, rent or distribute your information for purposes other than those disclosed here unless required by law or as authorized by you. We may share the information you provide among our subsidiaries and affiliates. We also may share the information with certain service providers we have retained. We take steps to require that service providers protect the information consistently with this Online Privacy Notice. These service providers are authorized to use the information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with law or legal process. Where we have knowledge that a service provider processes your personal information in a manner contrary to this Online Privacy Notice, we will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing. In addition, we may disclose information about you (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process; (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials; (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (4) if this is necessary to protect the vital interests of any person.

We also reserve the right to transfer personal information about you in the event we sell, transfer or merge all or a portion of the business or assets. Should such a sale, merger or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to direct the transferee to use information that is consistent with this Online Privacy Notice. 

**HOW WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We seek to ensure that any personal information that we hold about you is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable based on data you provide in order to provide you with access to and services via this website. We seek to collect personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for these purposes.

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information. 

We educate our employees and strive to maintain appropriate standards of conduct with regard to the protection of personal information. 

We take steps to require that third parties who assist in our provision of services abide by all applicable privacy laws and prohibit them from using your information other than in connection with the services they have been engaged to provide. 

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

Our website may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from Fragomen. Linked sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by Fragomen, we are not responsible for the sites’ content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

This Online Privacy Notice may be updated periodically to reflect new site features or changes in our information practices. We will post a notice on our website to advise of any significant changes to this Online Privacy Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated. 

If you have any questions or comments about this Cookies Notice, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at:

Attn: Office of General Counsel   
Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP   
90 Matawan Road   
P.O. Box 2001   
Matawan, New Jersey 07747   
USA 

Please see our Legal Notices.  
 _Last Updated: April 29, 2013_

___________________________________

___________________________________

EFFECTIVE DATE: March 25, 2015

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, Fragomen Global Immigration Services, LLC and their local entities, members and affiliates (collectively, “Fragomen”) use “cookies” on our websites.  Cookies are text files that are placed on your browser, mobile device or computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites.

We use cookies to ensure our websites function properly and to improve user experience. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest.

We use “session cookies,” which will expire when you close your browser. We also use “persistent cookies,” which have a set expiration date and will be stored on your browser, mobile device or computer until the date is reached or you delete your cookies.

Below is a list of the types of cookies used on our websites:

Our websites use session cookies to maintain information about each visit to our websites and enable essential functionality. This cookie does not contain any personal information and is deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

This sessional cookie is essential to help ensure that our websites load efficiently by distributing visits across multiple web servers. The cookie does not contain any personal information and is deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

We use Google Analytics, a service provided by Google, to help us understand how visitors use our web site. This allows us to improve the quality and content of our websites. 

For further information about the sessional and persistent cookies used as part of Google Analytics, as well as information about how Google uses this information, please see: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/>

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, be notified when you receive a new cookie, delete existing cookies and block all cookies.  Information is generally located in the ‘options’ or ‘preferences’ menu, or in the ‘Help’ option. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features.

By using our website, you consent to our use and placement of cookies as described in this Notice. If you wish to withdraw your consent at any stage, you will need to disable the settings on your browser as described above.

This Cookies Notice may be updated periodically without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices.  We will post a notice on our applicable websites or materials to advise of any significant changes to our Cookies Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated.  While this Cookies Notice is designed to comply with most data privacy laws and represents “best practices,” in certain countries additional or different procedures not inconsistent with this Cookies Notice may apply as necessary to satisfy local legal requirements.

If you have any questions or comments about this Cookies Notice, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at:

Attn: Data Privacy Office

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP

90 Matawan Road

P.O. Box 2001

Matawan, New Jersey 07747

USA

___________________________________

**ONLINE PRIVACY NOTICE**

EFFECTIVE DATE: May 10, 2010

Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP, Fragomen Global LLP, and their related affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively “Fragomen”) respect your concerns about privacy. This Online Privacy Notice applies only to personal information collected on [http://www.fragomen.com](http://www.fragomen.com/). This notice describes the types of personal information we collect on this website, how we may use that information and with whom we share it. Our Online Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. We also tell you how you can reach us to answer any questions you may have about our online privacy practices.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT  **

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

If you email us through the “Contact Us” link on this site, you may choose to provide personal information to us such as your name, email address, resume or CV. You may choose to provide additional information as well. We use the information you provide to respond to and communicate with you about your questions and comments. 

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT BY AUTOMATED MEANS**

We may collect certain information by automated means when you visit this website, such as how many users visited the site and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our websites to our visitors. We collect this information through “cookies” and IP addresses. 

**COOKIES**

Like many organizations, we may use “cookies” on this website. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. We may use cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site.

Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all our website features. 

**LOG FILES, USAGE DATA AND IP ADDRESSES**

Log files are web server files (containing information such as domain name or IP address, URL, http response code, or the date and duration of your visit) that are automatically created when an Internet user visits a website. An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our website, our servers log your IP address. In combination with other data, this information helps us understand which features are of interest to our visitors and the regions of the world where these visitors are located. In addition, log files help detect disruptions that may interfere with the provision of our website. 

We do not disclose personal information about visitors to this website, except as described here. We will not sell, share, transfer, rent or distribute your information for purposes other than those disclosed here unless required by law or as authorized by you. We may share the information you provide among our subsidiaries and affiliates. We also may share the information with certain service providers we have retained. We take steps to require that service providers protect the information consistently with this Online Privacy Notice. These service providers are authorized to use the information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with law or legal process. Where we have knowledge that a service provider processes your personal information in a manner contrary to this Online Privacy Notice, we will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing. In addition, we may disclose information about you (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process; (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials; (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (4) if this is necessary to protect the vital interests of any person.

We also reserve the right to transfer personal information about you in the event we sell, transfer or merge all or a portion of the business or assets. Should such a sale, merger or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to direct the transferee to use information that is consistent with this Online Privacy Notice. 

**HOW WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We seek to ensure that any personal information that we hold about you is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable based on data you provide in order to provide you with access to and services via this website. We seek to collect personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for these purposes.

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information. 

We educate our employees and strive to maintain appropriate standards of conduct with regard to the protection of personal information. 

We take steps to require that third parties who assist in our provision of services abide by all applicable privacy laws and prohibit them from using your information other than in connection with the services they have been engaged to provide. 

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

Our website may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from Fragomen. Linked sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by Fragomen, we are not responsible for the sites’ content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

This Online Privacy Notice may be updated periodically to reflect new site features or changes in our information practices. We will post a notice on our website to advise of any significant changes to this Online Privacy Notice and indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated. 

If you have any questions or comments about this Cookies Notice, please contact us by email at [dataprivacy@fragomen.com](mailto:dataprivacy@fragomen.com). You also may write to us at:

Attn: Office of General Counsel   
Fragomen, Del Rey, Bernsen & Loewy, LLP   
90 Matawan Road   
P.O. Box 2001   
Matawan, New Jersey 07747   
USA 

Please see our Legal Notices.  
 _Last Updated: April 29, 2013_

___________________________________

This statement is made on behalf of Fragomen (GB) Limited and Fragomen LLP (the "Fragomen UK") in respect of its actions and activities during the financial year ending 31 December 2018, pursuant to section 54(1) of the Modern Slavery Act 2015 (the "MSA").

Fragomen UK is part of "Fragomen Worldwide" ("Fragomen"), which is a professional immigration services business made up of law firms and consultancies in more than 40 offices worldwide. In countries where Fragomen does not have offices or in-house practice groups, we work with carefully selected local advisors to deliver services to our clients in more than 170 countries.

As a professional services organisation, we consider the risk of modern slavery existing within our business to be low. However, to ensure that we are compliant with all applicable legislation, and because of our commitment to the eradication of modern slavery and human trafficking, we have established a cross-functional working group, led by our Executive Committee and Leadership Team, to: identify and assess potential risk areas in our supply chains; mitigate the risks of slavery and human trafficking occurring in our supply chains; monitor potential risk areas; and protect whistle-blowers.

Fragomen UK has a zero tolerance approach to modern slavery of any kind within our operations and supply chain. Our positive contribution to the work of our clients is matched by our commitment to running our own operations responsibly. Therefore, we are committed to ensuring that slavery, human trafficking, child labour and any other abuse of human rights has not place in or around our organisation. We are proud of the steps that we have taken to combat slavery and human trafficking, and pleased to reinforce that commitment through this statement.

In the last year, Fragomen UK has fulfilled our principal objectives in relation to the MSA by taking significant steps to raise awareness of its requirements and engaging with its detail with our staff and key suppliers:

  * Online training on the MSA's requirements and the escalation of concerns, is mandatory for our UK employees; and

  * In contractual agreements and compliance statements, we have obtained warranties and undertakings from our key suppliers and business partners that there is no slavery, servitude, forced or compulsory human labour, abuse of power over vulnerable individuals, human trafficking or any other form of exploitation in any part of their businesses or supply chains.

Over the next 12-18 months, we plan to refine our online training and increase our engagement with external stakeholders in relation to MSA-related risks.

_Last Updated: November 2018_
